Samuel C. Phillips map and chart collection
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress
Samuel C. Phillips map and chart collection 1947-1971
G3195 coll .P5 Phillips
Phillips, Samuel C.
32 items
3 folders
Geography and Map Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection consists of 32 maps and charts that depict Apollo missions and the Northern Hemisphere.
Provenance
Mrs. Betty Ann Phillips donated the materials from 1991 to 1993.
Materials Cataloged Separately
Samuel C. Phillips papers, 1929-1990 (bulk 1958-1989)
Catalog Record: https://lccn.loc.gov/mm93080934
Access and Restrictions
The Samuel C. Phillips map and chart collection collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Geography and Map Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Samuel C. Phillips was a U.S. Air Force officer, space agency official, intelligence agency director, and defense industry executive.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of 32 maps and charts that depict Apollo missions and the Northern Hemisphere.
Arrangement
The Samuel C. Phillips map and chart collection collection is organized in two series:
Series I: U.S. Air Force charts of the Northern Hemisphere
Series II: Apollo mission charts
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Phillips, Samuel C. (Samuel Cochran), 1921-1990, compiler.
Organizations
Apollo 12 (Spacecraft); Apollo 8 (Spacecraft); United States. Aeronautical Chart Service; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration
Subjects
Artificial satellites--Moon--Orbits--Maps
Places
Moon--Maps.; Northern Hemisphere--Maps.
Form/Genre
Aeronautical charts.; Maps.
Container List
- Series I: U.S. Air Force charts of the Northern Hemisphere (Folder 1)
  1:48,000,000.
  Polar Stereographic projection.
  - Political & Time Chart GH - 1a, 1947, 1
  - Physical Relief Chart GH - 2a, 1947, 2
  - Temperature Provinces and Ocean Currents Chart GH - 3a, 1947, 3
  - Climatic Chart GH - 5a, 1947, 4
  - Density of Population Chart GH - 7a, 1947, 5
  - Economic Chart GH - 8a, 1947, 6
  - Transportation Chart GH - 9a, 1947, 7
  - Isobars and Prevailing Winds Chart January GH - 10a, 1947, 8
  - Isobars and Prevailing Winds Chart July GH - 11a, 1947, 9
  - January Climatic Zones GH - 19a, 1947, 10
  - April Climatic Zones GH - 22a, 1947, 11
  - July Cliumatic Zones GH - 25a, 1947, 12
  - October Climatic Zones GH - 26a, 1947, 13
  - Gnomic Tracking Chart GT 50a, 1947, 14
    Gnomonic projection
- Series II: Apollo mission charts
  - Folder 2: Apollo mission charts (Folder 2)
    - Deep Space Re-entry recovery planning chart (NDR) Apollo Mission 8, 15
    - Apollo Earth orbit chart (AEO) Apollo Mission 8. Sheet of 1 of 3. Revolution 1., 1968, 16
    - Apollo Earth orbit chart (AEO) Apollo Mission 8. Sheet of 2 of 3. Revolution 2., 1968, 17
    - Apollo Earth orbit chart (AEO) Apollo Mission 8. Sheet of 3 of 3. Revolution 3., 1968, 18
    - Apollo Earth orbit chart (AEO) Apollo Mission 12., 1969, 19
    - Apollo Lunar orbit chart (ALO) Apollo Mission 12, 1969, 20
    - 14 Nov. 1969 launch date targets of opportunity flight chart. SKB 32100097-301, 1969, 21
      1:7,500,000.
      Mercator projection.
    - Lunar chart edition 1, 4 December 1968, 22
      1:11,000,000.
      2 copies.
    - Lunar chart 1st Edition, 8 October 1969, 23
  - Folder 3: Apollo mission charts (Folder 3)
    - Lunar landing site monitoring photomap (ILM) landing site 7, 24
    - Ascent monitoring chart SEB 321 00025-006. 14 November 1969 site 7, 25
    - Ascent monitoring chart. SEB 321 00025-006. 16 November 1969 site 5, 26
    - 1st edition LM descent monitoring chart - LMD (PDI to landing) 4 October 1969. Landing site No. 5, 27
    - 2nd edition LM descent monitoring chart - LMD (PDI to landing) 3 October 1969. Landing site No. 7, 28
    - LM orbit monitor chart Apollo 14. January 31, 1971. SKB 32100083-373. S/N., 29
    - Apollo Translunar/Transearth trajectory plotting chart, 1968, 30
      Apollo Mission 8.
    - Apollo Translunar/Transearth plotting chart, 1971, 31
      Apollo Mission 14.
    - Pacific Reovery Planning Chart, 1969, 32